hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome to episode 27 of the
tactics game in unity essential scene
system
okay we want to introduce a level on
experience information to the status
panel so let's make an experience Bar
for our character by duplicating HP bar
let's rename them in the hierarchy and
add some text to make it more clear what
purpose of those bars
good now in status panel the script we
want to pass the info about character
level to those new objects so we need to
add fields for them so we will be able
to reference them
reference them in the editor
then in update status set the values
now we should see experience bar
reflecting character experience well and
its level
good prefab the status panel because we
will be using it on other scenes soon
so now let's go back to our combat scene
and we will want to replace our older
status panel with a new fancy status
panel
before we head the status panel
component on the game manager but now we
will have status panel component on the
well status panel so let's remove the
status panel component from game manager
and instead add status panel manager to
the status panel object
and that should be enough actually let's
test this
good
this episode is brought to you by
General support of people on patreon and
members on YouTube if you want to join
them link to my patreon in the
description Android button available
right now on YouTube
so imagine you want to introduce a new
stage a new Battlefield each and every
Battlefield you shall exactly the same
components with only terrain and some
stage specific objects being different
each Battlefield will have game manager
each Battlefield will have camera or
player and opponent forces each
Battlefield will have canvas with UI
shoving information
so each Battlefield will be sharing some
essential components and objects for
combat to function so we can separate
essential components for combat into an
essential for combat scene which will be
always loaded when combat is running
meanwhile the terrain and level or stage
or whatever you can call it
specific elements will be loaded
additively to this scene it pretty much
means you will have two scenes loaded at
the same time the combat essential scene
and Stage specific stage scene
create a new empty scene make sure it is
additive
let's call it combat stage
and rename the sample scene with all our
combat systems into combat essential
scene
future Greg here if you created a scene
but forgot to set it to be additive what
you need to do is to drag and drop the
essential scene which currently is
called sample scene and the newly
created combat stage scene into the
hierarchy and you will see them being
loaded exactly the same way as it is
right now
when you operate in this kind of
environment you must make sure that your
combat essential scene is an active
scene which you can check by making sure
the name of the scene is highlighted and
written in bold cases
and if it's not active make it by
clicking set active scene like this good
so now we want to move our stage
environment to the combat stage
don't worry about the errors we will fix
them soon
so we have moved terrain and everything
related to the stage environment to the
combat stage
now we need to fix all these errors on
the stage scene create a new object
called stage manager
inside we will be storing reference to
everything important on this stage scene
which we want to be able to easily
reference so our combat works with the
Grid on the stage you know because
you're moving characters from this Grid
or attacking objects on this grid etc
etc so create a field so we can
reference the grid of the stage scene
reference Grid in the editor
move character to the combat scene
dependent on the mission you want to
replace some enemies or your characters
so our designer will be able to place
characters on the stage while designing
the stage and he doesn't need to touch
anything in the essential scene
now we need to solve issue with
references in the mouse input
here's a reference to the stage grid
in the move character we need to clear
the reference to the stage grid
in the marker we need to Cache reference
to the stage grid
and in the select character we need to
Cache reference to the stage grid
then we need to pass a reference to
highlight system so in the stage manager
make two public Fields one for move
highlight and one for attack highlight
reference them in the editor
when I think about it we might move
those highlight pointers into essential
system later on for now let's keep them
on the grid object
then we need to catch reference to the
highlighters in the movement command
and in the character attack we need to
catch a reference to the grid and grid
highlight for attacks
and in the clears utility we will need
to add field for pathfinding into Stage
manager
don't worry I understand it is a little
confusing right now but over the course
of coming episode we will continue
refactoring the systems and it will
become way more clear why we are making
these changes
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave your comment below if
you want to support me link in the
description special thank you to
Stormbreaker 9000 and the sword has do
for their generous support with best
regards see you in the next episode